我想为大家展示一下，认证加密在现实中的应用
So I want to show you how authenticated
encryption is used in the real world, so
我们用TLS作为一个例子，来看看TLS是如何工作的
let's use TLS as an example and see how
TLS works. So data encryption in TLS is
在TLS中，数据加密使用的协议叫做TLS记录协议
done using a protocol called a TLS record
protocol. In this protocol, every TLS
在这个协议栈，每个TLS记录都以一个报文头开始，
我们待会将看到报文头的格式
record starts with a header, we'll see the
structure of the header in just a minute,
报文头后面接加密的数据，由一方发送到另一方的
followed by encrypted data that is sent
from one side to the other. In TLS, it so
在TLS中，记录的长度最多为16KB
happens that the records are at most
sixteen kilobytes and if more data than
如果需要发送多于16KB的数据，那么
sixteen kilobytes needs to be sent, then
basically the record is fragmented into
一个记录需要被拆分成多个记录。现在，TLS
使用了单向密钥
multiple records. Now TLS uses what's
called unidirectional keys, meaning that
意思是从浏览器到服务器的单方向的密钥，
而从服务器到浏览器也有另一个密钥
there's one key from browser to server,
and there's a separate key from server to
所以发送信息从浏览器到服务器，用一个密钥
browser. So one key is used for sending
messages from a browser to the server, and
发送信息从服务器到浏览器，用另一个密钥
the other key is used from sending
messages from the server to the browser,
当然，服务器和浏览器双方都知道这些密钥
and of course both sides, both the server
and the browser, know both of these keys.
为了更清楚，我说浏览器会使用这个密钥来发送数据
And just to be clear I'll say the browser
will use this key to send data to the
给服务器，我们会使用这个密钥来读取从服务器发来的数据
server and we'll use this key to read data
from the server and the server basically
而服务器用另一方向的密钥来做一模一样的事情
does exactly the same thing just with the
opposite keys. Now these keys, both of
双方向的密钥都是由TLS密钥交换协议生成的
these keys are actually generated by the
TLS key exchange protocol which we're
我们将在本课程的第二部分讨论之。现在我假设
gonna talk about in the second part of the
course. Right now I'm gonna assume that
这些密钥已经被建立了。服务器和浏览器都知道这些密钥
these keys have already been established.
They're known to both the server and the
现在浏览器和服务器想使用这些密钥来交换信息
browser, and now the browser and server
want to exchange information using those
TLS记录协议使用了所谓的基于状态的加密
keys. So the TLS record protocol uses
what's called stateful encryption, which
意思是，每个数据包的加密是使用
means that the encryption of every packet
is done using certain state that's
浏览器和服务器内部维护的特定状态来完成的
maintained inside of the browser and the
server. In particular the state that's of
特别地，我们感兴趣的状态是这些64位计数器
interest to us are these 64 bit counters,
again there are two 64 bit counters. One
一个用于从浏览器到服务器的通信，
另一个用于从服务器到浏览器的通信
for traffic from browser to server, and
one from traffic from the server to the
当会话被首次初始化后，这些计数器被初始化为0
browser. These counters are initialized to
zero when the session is first
然后每次发送记录时，它们都增加
initialized, and they're incremented every
time a record is sent. So every time the
每次浏览器发送一个记录给服务器时，浏览器都会增加这个计数器
browser sends a record to the server, the
browser will go ahead and increment this
当服务器收到这个记录时，它会增加它这边的计数器
counter. When the server receives that
record, it'll go ahead and increment the
当服务器发送记录给浏览器时
counter on its side. And when the server
sends a record to the browser, he'll go
它会增加第二个计数器，当浏览器接收到这个记录时
ahead and increment the second counter and
again when the browser receives this
它会增加它这边的计数器
record it'll go ahead and increment its
copy of this counter. So this state these
一个状态，两个计数器。这个状态存在于浏览器和服务器双方
two counters basically this state exists
both on the browser and on the server and
随着记录由一方发送，另一方接收，状态被合理地更新
it's updated appropriately as records as
sent from one to the other and received
现在这些计数器的目的，我们一会将看到
by the appropriate side. Now the purpose
of these counters as we'll see in just a
是为了阻止重放攻击，这样攻击者不能简单地保存记录
minute is to prevent replay attacks so
than an attacker can't simply record the record
然后待会再重放，因为到时候计数器一定已经增加了
and then replay at a later time because by
then the counters will have to be
我们看记录协议的工作细节
incremented. Okay, so let's look at the
details of how the record protocol works.
特别地，我要为大家展示这个强制性的密码套件
In particular I'll show you kind of the
mandatory cipher suit which is encryption
加密使用AES-CBC，MAC使用HMAC-SHA1。
记住TLS使用了一个MAC，然后加密
using AES-CBC and MACing using HMAC-SHA1. Okay,
so remember, TLS uses a MAC, then encrypt,
MAC算法是HMAC-SHA1
where the MAC algorithm is HMAC-SHA1, and the encryption
加密算法是AES128用CBC模式。我们看浏览器给服务器发送数据
algorithm is AES128 in CBC mode. Okay, so
let's look at how the browser sends data
我说过，使用的是从浏览器到服务器的密钥
to the server, which, as I said, is done
using the browser to server key. Now, the
从浏览器到服务器的密钥本身，是由一个MAC密钥
和一个加密密钥组成
browser to server key itself, is made up
of a MAC key and an encryption key. Two
如我所说，两个单独的密钥在会话起始阶段就被协商好了
separated keys that are again as I said
negotiated during session setup. And again
我想说的绝对清楚。从浏览器到服务器有一个单独的密钥
I wanna be absolutely clear. There is a
separate key for browser to server and a
从服务器到浏览器有另一个单独的密钥。所以
总的来说，一共有4个密钥
separate key from server to browser. So
there, overall, there are four keys. Two
两个是MAC密钥，两个是加密密钥，每个被使用在合适的方向
MAC keys, and two encryption keys, each
one used in the appropriate direction.
这里我写下了TLS数据包的结构图
Okay, so here I wrote down the diagram of
what a TLS packet looks like. It begins
它以一个报文头开头，包含了数据包的类型、协议版本号
with a header that contains the type of
the packet, the version number for the
以及数据包的长度。注意到数据包的长度
protocol, and the length of the packet.
Notice the length of the packet it sends
是以明文形式发送的。加密数据、加密特定记录时
in the clear. Now, when the encrypting
data, a certain record, the encryption
加密流程如下：当然，取密钥为输入
procedure works as follows. Of course, it
takes key as input, and it takes the
取当前状态为输入，然后如下工作。
current status input. And then it works as
follows. What it'll do is first of all
首先它会计算下面数据的MAC，这是取MAC的实际的封装数据
it would MAC the following data, while
here's the actual payload that's MACed but
不过报文头也在MAC的计算中，另外，计数器的当前值
the header is also MACed. In addition the
counter, the current value of the counter
也在MAC的计算中，当然，所有计数器增加
is also MACed and of course, it's all the
counters are incremented to indicate
以表示又一个记录被发送了。这里有趣的是
the fact that one more record has
been sent. Now the interesting thing here
即使计数器的值包含在标签里
is that even though the value of the
counter is included in the tag. You notice
大家注意，计数器的值实际上永远不会在记录中发送
the value of the counter is actually never
sent in the record, and the reason it
它不用被放在记录里发送的原因是，另一端的服务器
doesn't need to be sent in the record is
that the server on the other side already
已经知道了计数器的值，所以它不需要
knows what the value of the counter needs
to be. So it doesn't need to be told in
在记录中被告知计数器的值，它隐性地知道这个值
the record what the value of the counter
is. It implicitly already knows what it
当它要验证这个MAC时，它可以使用它认为的计数器的值
is, and when it's gonna verify the MAC, it
could just use the value that it thinks
来验证这个MAC。这是个有趣的方法
the counter should be and verify the MAC
in that fashion. Okay, so this is kind of
尽管双方都维护着这些计数器
an interesting approach, where even though
the two sides maintain these counters that
这些计数器具备新鲜值的功能，
没有理由把新鲜值放在记录里
function as nonces, there is no
reason to send the nonces in the record,
因为双方实际上都知道每个收到的记录的计数器
because both sides actually already know
what counters they're expecting every
那么这是标签。我们说过，这个标签计算的范围
record that they receive. Okay, so that's
the tag. The tag is computed, as we said,
是这个三元组数据。下件事是把标签附在数据后面
over this triple data. The next thing that
happens is that the tag is concatenated to
记着，这是先MAC后加密。所以这里我们计算了MAC
the data. Remember, this is MAC-then-Encrypt. So here, we computed the MAC. Now
我们会将数据和标签一并加密。所以报文头、数据
we're gonna encrypt the data along with
the tag. So the header, the data, and the
和标签被补齐到AES分组。我想我们说过这种补齐了
tag are padded to the AES block, and I
think we already said that this pad, if
如果补齐的长度是5个字节，那么补齐就是简单地
the pad length is five, then the pad is
done by simply writing the byte five, five
写5个5。如果补齐长度是5个字节，补齐将是55555
times. If the pad length is to be 5, the
pad would just be 55555. And then we CBC
然后我们用加密密钥来进行CBC加密，我们计算
数据和标签的CBC加密
encrypt using the encryption key, we CBC
encrypt the data and the tag. And we do
我们使用一个新鲜的随机IV，它待会被嵌入到密文中
that using a fresh random IV, which is
later embedded in the cipher text. And
然后我们在结果前附上报文头、报文类型、版本号和长度
then we prepend the header, the type,
the version and the length. And that gives
这就给出了整个TLS记录，然后发送给服务器
us the entire TLS record, which is then
sent over to the server. So the grayed out
结构图中灰色的区域对应于被加密的数据
fields in this diagram correspond to
encrypted data, and the white fields
白色的区域对应于明文数据。所以大家可以看到
这是TLS的"先MAC后加密"的实现
correspond to plaintext data. So you can
see that this is TLS's implementation of
唯一与"先MAC后加密"的区别在于
MAC then encrypt. The only difference from
basic MAC then encrypt is the fact that
有一个状态，即这个计数器，被包含在MAC值里
there is a state, namely this counter is
being included in the value of the MAC.
我也说过，这是为了阻止重放攻击。我们来看为什么能阻止重放
And again as I said that's done to prevent
replays. So let's see why that prevents
特别地，我们看记录协议是如何解密到来的记录
replays. In particular, let's see how the
record protocol decrypts an incoming
那么，这里来了一个加密的记录
record. So, here comes an incoming
encrypted record. And again, the server is
服务器又将使用对应的、从浏览器到服务器的密钥
going to use its own key that corresponds
to data, from browser to server. And its
以及从浏览器到服务器的计数器。首先
own browser to server counter. And the
first thing it's going to do, is it's
我们使用加密密钥来解密记录。解密后，
going to decrypt the record using the
encryption key. After encryption, it's
(口误：encryption->decryption)
检测补齐长度，换句话说，如果补齐长度是5字节
going to check the format of the pad. In
other words, if the pad length is five
检查结尾是否真是55555
bytes, it's going to check that it really
is five, five, five, five, five. And if
如果不是，它将发送一个坏记录MAC警告
it's not, it's gonna send a bad record MAC
alert message and terminate the
并断开连接。如果需要发送更多记录，
那就必须协商一个新的会话密钥
connection. So that a new session key will
have to be negotiated if more records need
如果补齐格式是正确的，去除补齐是很容易的
to be sent. If the pad format is correct,
then removing the pad is really easy. All
服务器只需看补齐的最后的字节，比如说
the server does is it looks at the last
byte of the pad, say the last byte is
最后一个字节等于5，那么它就去除记录的最后5个字节
equal to five, and, then, it removes the
last five bytes of the record. By doing
这就去除补齐了。接下来从记录中提取标签
that it strips off the pad. The next thing
it's gonna do is it's gonna extract the
这里网页数据藏在这个记录里
tag from the record. So, this would be the
web sequence bytes inside of the record.
也就是我去除补齐后剩下的记录
So, this would be the, the trailing bytes
in the record after we remove the pad, and
然后会验证报文头、数据和计数器值的标签
then it's gonna verify the tag on the
header, the data and its value of counter.
如果MAC不能验证，将发送一个警告，坏记录MAC
And if the MAC doesn't verify again, it's
gonna send an alert, bad record MAC, and
然后断开连接。如果标签通过验证，就去除标签
tear down the connection. And if the pad
does verify, it's gonna remove the tag,
(这里pad应该为tag)
去除报文头，剩下的记录是明文数据
remove the header, and the remaining part
of the record is the plain text data
也就是给应用的数据。现在，大家可以看到如果记录被重放了
that's given to the application. Now, you
can see if a record is ever replayed, in
换句话说，如果攻击者记下了某个记录，
other words if an attacker records a
particular record and then replays it to the
然后稍后重放它给服务器，到时候计数器的值已经变了
server at a later time, then, by then the
value of the counter would have changed
因此被重放的记录的标签将不会通过验证
and as a result the tag on the replayed
record would simply not verify because the
因为这个标签的计算使用了计数器的值
tag was computed using one value of the
counter but with the replayed record as
但对于重放的记录来说，被服务器收到后，计数器的值
received at the server, the value of the
counter of the server is different from
已经和计算记录里的标签时的计数器值不一样了，
因此这个标签将不会通过验证
the value that was used to compute a tag
and as a result the tag was not verified.
这些计数器很优雅，简单地阻止了重放攻击
So these counters are very elegant and
simple way for preventing replays and the
这样做很好的一点是，因为双方都隐性地知道
nice thing about this is because both
sides know the value of the counter implicitly
计数器的值，记录中永远不需要发送计数器了
there's never a need to send the
counter in the record itself. So the
所以计数器本身并不增加密文L的长度
counter itself doesn't increase the length
of cipher text L. Now, we already
现在，我们已经提到过这个方法用来认证加密
mentioned that this particular approach
to, authenticated encryption, namely, MAC,
先MAC，然后使用CBC加密，事实上是认证加密
then encrypt, using CBC encryption, is, in
fact, authenticated encryption. However,
不过它只有当解密时没有信息泄漏，才是认证加密
it's only authenticated encryption if no
other information is leaked during
我们将看到一些犀利的针对TLS的攻击
decryption. And we're going to see some
acute attacks on TLS if there is
针对解密时有信息泄漏的情况。我应该说
information being leaked during
decryption. I should say that this bad
这个坏记录MAC警告对应于解密算法输出
record MAC alert basically corresponds to
the decryption algorithm outputting this
拒绝符号⊥，意思是密文是无效的
reject symbol, the bottom symbol. Meaning
that the cipher text is invalid. And as
只要无法区分为什么密文被拒绝了
long as there's no way to differentiate
between why the cipher text was rejected,
换句话说，解密者暴露了拒绝的事实
in other words the decrypter only exposes
the fact that a rejection took place but
但它不说为什么会拒绝。事实上这是一个认证加密系统
it doesn't say why the rejection happened
this is in fact an authenticated
但是，如果区分和暴露了为什么
encryption system. However, if you
differentiate and expose why the cipher
密文会被拒绝，是否是因为坏的补齐，
抑或是因为坏的MAC
text was rejected whether it was because
of a bad pad or because of a bad MAC then
那么就会有一个非常犀利的攻击，
我们将在下一节看到它
it turns out there's a very acute attack.
Which we're gonna see in the next segment.
目前我给大家展示了TLS 1.1版本
What I showed you so far is called TLS
Version 1.1. It turns out that earlier
实际上在这之前的TLS版本有严重的错误
versions of TLS actually had significant
mistakes in it, and as a result, the
较早的记录协议对很多攻击是脆弱的
earlier Record Protocol is vulnerable to a
number of attacks. The first mistake is
第一个错误是CBC加密使用的IV是可以预测的
that the IV used in CBC Encryption is
predictable. And we said earlier that in
我们之前说过在CBC里，如果IV是可预测的，
那么会造成CBC加密不是CPA安全的
CBC, if the IV is predictable then the
resulting CBC Encryption is not CPA
在较早版本的TLS里，TLS 1.0或更早
Secure. Well, in this older version of
TLS, TLS 1.0 and earlier, the IV for the
下一记录所用的IV就是当前记录的最后一个密文分组
next record is simply the last cipher text
block of the current record. And as a
因此，如果攻击者可以观察到当前的记录
result, if the adversary can observe the
current record, he knows the IV for the
他就会知道下一记录的IV，这就允许他破坏
下一个记录的语义安全
next record and that will allow him to
break the semantic security of the next
得到的机制不是CPA安全的。它不仅不是CPA安全的
record. So the resulting scheme is not CPA
secure. But not only is it not CPA secure,
事实上，有一个非常系里的攻击叫做BEAST攻击
in fact, there is a very acute attack
called a BEAST attack that's able to decrypt
可以解密TLS记录的最初部分
the initial part of the TLS record
simply based on the fact that this scheme
因为TLS这个机制不是语义安全的。我应该说
这种选前一个记录的最后一个分组为IV的方法
is not semantically secure. So, I should
say that this method of choosing the IV to
叫做链式IV。大家应该记住
be the last block of the previous record
is called chained IV's. And you should
这种方法不应在实际中使用
remember that this, actually should not be
used in practice because it always, always
因为它总是会造成攻击。正因为此，
TLS 1.1改用了所谓的显性IV
leads to an attack. Because of this TLS
1.1 moved to what's called, explicit IV's
其中每个TLS记录有它自己的随机的不可预测的IV
where every TLS record has its own random
unpredictable IV. And that's fixed the
一旦浏览器和服务器升级到了TLS 1.1，问题就会解决
problem as soon as browsers and servers
move to TLS 1.1, this will no longer be an
TLS 1.0以及更早版本的另一个错误是
issue. Now another mistake that was done
in TLS 1.0 and earlier, enabled what's
采用了所谓的补齐神谕，我们下节再讨论它
called a padding oracle, which is
something that we're going to talk about
如果密文因为补齐无效而被拒绝了
in the next segment, were what happened
was, that if the cipher text was rejected
服务器会发送一个警告说，加密失败
due to an invalid pad, the server was sent
back an alert message saying decryption
同时，如果密文是因为错误的MAC而被拒绝
failed. Whereas if the cipher text was
rejected due to a bad MAC, the server will
服务器会发送一个坏记录MAC警告。因此
send back a bad record MAC alert. As a
result, and adversary who observes the
攻击者观察这些服务器返回的警告，就可以得知
密文的补齐是否是有效的
alert sends back from the server, can tell
whether the pad in the cipher text was
这样引入了一个非常重要的攻击叫做补齐攻击
valid or invalid. And this introduces a
very significant attack called a padding
我们下节讨论之。TLS 1.1对此的解决方法是
attack, which we're gonna talk about in
the next segment. The solution to this and
不再报告解密失败
TLS 1.1, was basically to say that,
instead of reporting decryption failed
而是报告一个坏MAC，即使补齐是错误的
here, we're gonna report a bad record MAC,
even if the pad is incorrect. And, as a
因此，通过简单地看服务器返回的是哪种警告
result, simply looking at which alert is
sent back from the server, an attacker
攻击者不能识别，密文的被拒绝，是因为坏补齐还是坏MAC
can't tell if a cipher text is rejected
because of a bad pad or a bad MAC. So this
这就隐藏了这个信息。这里的教训是
tries to mask this information. Now the
lesson from this is that when decryption
当解密失败时，永远不要解释为什么。
我猜老TLS版本这样设计，可能是来自
fails, you should never ever explain why,
I guess this is something that comes out
网络协议里的惯例：如果发生失败的情况，
就想告诉对方为什么会失败
of networking protocols where if there is
a failure you wanna tell the peer why the
但在密码学里，如果你解释为什么会失败
failure occurred, where in cryptography if
you explain why the failure occurred that
很可能会造成一个攻击。换句话说，当解密失败时
very often leads to an attack. In other
words when decryption fails just output
只输出拒绝，从不解释为什么拒绝，光拒绝就行了
reject and don't explain why the reject
actually happens just reject the ciphertext.
现在我们已经看了TLS 1.1。我们再看一个已被破解的协议
Okay, so now that we've seen TLS 1.1,
let's see a broken protocol. So of course
当然我总是喜欢拿802.11b WEP开刀，这个WEP里
几乎所有的东西都不对
I always like to pick on 802.11b WEP,
which pretty much got everything wrong. So
我们看它是如何不能提供认证加密的
let's see how not to provide authenticated
encryption. So let me remind you how
我帮大家看一下802.11b WEP是如何工作的。
笔记本想发送一条信息给接入点
802.11b WEP works. Basically there's a
message that the laptop wants to send to
首先，笔记本计算信息的循环冗余校验码(CRC)
the access point. The first thing that
happens is it, the laptop computes a
然后把CRC校验码附在信息的后面
cyclic redundancy checksum on the message
and concatenates the CRC checksum to the
然后结果用流密码加密，流密码用的是RC4
message. Then the result is encrypted
using a stream cipher, in particular RC4.
大家回忆一下，WEP使用的密钥是一个初始IV值
If you recall, the key that's used is the
concatenation of an initial value IV
这个IV每个数据包都会变，再联结上一个长密钥K
that changes per packet and the long term
key K. And then the IV along with the
然后IV和密文一并传递给对方。现在我们已经看了
cipher text are transmitted to the other
side. Now we've already saw two
这种方法的两个问题。一个是IV会重复
problems with this approach. One was if
the IV is ever repeated and in fact it is
事实上这个IV一重复，那你就能实施一个二次密码本攻击
gonna be repeated then you get a two time
pad attack. And the other problem
另一个问题是WEP使用了关联非常密切的密钥。换句话说
is that WEP uses very closely
related keys. In other words, the key is
密钥仅仅是IV联结上K，唯一改变的是IV
simply IV concatenated to K and the only
thing that changes are the IV so the key
而密钥K总是固定的，这意味着这些PRG密钥互相之间
is always fixed, which means that these
PRG keys are very closely related to one
关系非常紧密。我们说过，这里使用的PRG是RC4
another and as we said, the PRG that's
used here, RC4 is not designed for this
RC4不是为这种用法而设计的，他会完全被破解，
如果你使用关联密钥
type of use and it completely breaks
if you use it with related keys, and as a
因此WEP根本没有安全性可言。我想为大家展示
result WEP has no security at all.
What I want to show you is that even the
这里甚至使用了CRC机制，以试图提供完整性
CRC mechanism that's used here, in an
attempt to provide integrity and prevent
想阻止攻击者篡改密文
an adversary from tampering with the
cipher text, even that mechanism is
即便这个机制被完全破解了，
实际上在途中篡改密文也极为容易
completely broken, and it's actually very
easy to tamper with cipher texts en route.
我们看看怎么做。这个攻击利用了CRC校验和的一个性质
So let's see how that's done. The attack
uses a particular property of the CRC
CRC基本上是线性的，意思是如果我给你信息M的CRC校验码
check sum. Mainly the CRC is linear. What
that means is if I give you CRC of M, and
我让你计算M异或P的CRC，那么这是容易做到的
I ask you to compute CRC of M XOR P, then
it's very easy to do. Basically you'll
你只要计算某个广为人知的函数F(P)，再把这两结果异或
just compute some well known and public
function of F(P), you XOR these two together,
就得到了M异或P的CRC。某种意义上
and that in fact will give you CRC of
M XOR P. So in some sense the XOR comes out
这里的异或从括号里提取出来了，意味着CRC是线性的
of the parenthesis, and that basically
means the CRC is linear. Now here is how the
攻击如下。假设攻击者截获了某个数据包
attack works, suppose the adversary
intercepts a particular packet that's
送往接入点的数据包。现在数据包说
destined to the access point. Now the
packet say, sais it's destined for
它的目标端口是80，攻击者知道它是送往80端口的
destination port 80, and the attacker
knows that it's intended for destination
攻击者想修改密文
port 80 and what he wants to do is
modify the cipher texts such that now the
使得目标端口变成25，而不是80
destination port will say 25 instead of
80. And maybe the attacker can read
也许攻击者可以读取送往25端口的信息，
这样他就能获取数据包里的数据了
messages for port 25 and that's how he
actually obtains the actual data in the
记得CRC校验和是为了确保攻击者不能修改密文中的数据
packet. So recall that the CRC checksum
is there to make sure that exactly the
但是我想告诉大家，事实上
attacker cannot change data inside of the
cipher text. But I want to show you that
非常容易修改密文数据
in fact it's really easy to modify data in
the cipher text and CRC basically provides
CRC对篡改根本没有安全可言。我们看怎么做
no security against tampering at all. So
let's see how to do it. Well, what the
攻击者会对密文中代表80的那些字节
attacker would do is, he would basically
XOR some, a certain value XX into the byte
异或某些特定的值XX。现在他会异或
that represents the eight zero in the
cipher text. Now what he'll XOR in will
字符串25异或80，大家记得，如果我异或特定字符串XX
basically be the string 25 XOR 80 and you
remember that if I XOR a certain string XX
到密文里，密文由流密码生成
into the cipher text. That was created
using a stream cipher. When that cipher
当密文解密时，此处的明文也会变成异或了XX后的样子
gets, is decrypted, the plain text at this
position will also be XORed by XX. And as
因此在解密后，此处的明文会变成
a result after decryption the plain text
at this position basically will be the
原文80异或25异或80=25。所以在解密后
original 80 XOR 25 XOR 80 which gives us 25.
Okay? So after decryption the plain text
这里的明文变成了25。问题是，如果我们只做这些
of this position will now be 25. The
problem is that if that's all we did then
攻击还是会失败的，因为CRC校验和现在还不是有效的
this attack would fail because the CRC
check sum would now would not validate.
这里的CRC校验和是根据"80端口"的明文构建的，
但"25端口"是一个不同的明文
The CRC check sum was built with 80 as a
plain text but 25 is a different plain
需要一个不同的CRC。但这不是问题，因为
text and needs a different CRC. But it's
not a problem because what we can do is we
我们可以轻松修正这个CRC校验码，尽管CRC校验码也被加密了
can easily correct the check sum, the CRC
check sum, even though the CRC check sum
我们把密文中对应CRC校验码的部分
is encrypted. What we do is we XOR
F of XX into the cipher text at the place
与F(XX)异或，所以当密文解密后
where the CRC is supposed to be and as a
result, when the cipher text is decrypted
我们会得到正确的CRC校验和
what will happen is we'll get the correct
CRC check sum after decryption. So, the
这里有趣的事情是，尽管攻击者不知道
interesting thing that happened here is
even though the attacker doesn't know what
CRC校验和是什么，他依然可以利用CRC的线性性质进行修正
the CRC value is, he's able to correct it
using this linearity property such that
使得当密文解密时，明文中的CRC校验和是正确的
when the cipher text is decrypted the
correct CRC value appears in the plain
所以CRC的线性性质在这个攻击中扮演着重要角色
text. Okay? So the linearity property of
CRC plays a critical role in making this
结论是CRC校验和完全不提供完整性
attack works. The end conclusion here is
basically that a CRC check sum provides
来对抗主动攻击，CRC永远不能用于完整性机制
absolutely no integrity at all against
active attacks and it should never, ever,
如果你想提供完整性
ever be used as an integrity mechanism.
And instead if you want to provide
你应该使用一个密码学MAC，而不是随意设计的机制
integrity you're supposed to use a
cryptographic MAC not an ad hoc mechanism
比如CRC。现在我们已经看了认证加密
是如何在真实协议中实现的
like CRC. Okay, so now we've seen how
authenticated encryption is implemented in
比如TLS。下节我们看
a real world protocol, like TLS. In the
next segment, we're gonna look at real
针对认证加密实现的真实攻击
world attacks on authenticated encryption
implementations that happen to implement
这些加密实现恰好是不正确的
authenticated encryption incorrectly.